Jordan Skinner

Senior Full Stack Developer

+1 862 201-5656Troy, Michigan

@ jordanskinner072@gmail.com

@ linkedin.com/in/jordan-skinner-dev

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer and system administrator with over 10 years of experience in software engineering and developing new features and apps for different products and companies by using programming tools like React, React-Native, Redux, Vue.js, Angular, JavaScript(ES6), TypeScript, Node.js, Python, Laravel, PHP, Express, Figma and RESTfulAPI. Specialized in frontend with React, TypeScript, Vue.js, Responsive Design including HTML5, CSS and backend with Django, Node.js, AWS and Docker. Also specialized in large complex data migration and mining projects, refactoring code for improved performance, and debugging complex internal and external API integrations.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Narrativ Digital Agency

08/2021 - 01/2024

- · Worked on the admin and customer portals and rewrote them from Vue 2 to React/TypeScript.
- Developed a self-guided wizard for creating a dashboard. The front end was done using Angular and the back end using .Net Core. The database was a SQL server, and T-SQL was used for developing stored procedures.
- Refactored the existing code to improve the performance of a heavy React front-end by talking to Node.js and Express.js via REST API.
- Designed and developed 10+ RESTful APIs using Node.JS, Nest, PHP, Laravel, Python, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, AWS, Microsoft Azure and Google Cloud Platform.
- Delivered a full-stack web application using Django, MySQL, Bootstrap, and jQuery contained a repository of thousands of documents about financial datasets. It integrated with Jira for tracking alerts relating to data ingestion delays.
- Collaborated with the backend team to design, define, and implement GraphQL types and resolvers to provide the necessary data for frontend development while maintaining minimal calls to the database.
- Re-implemented crucial components of a monolithic video player back-end application in a new REST microservice architecture from the very beginning of the project to production release and later support.
- Supported and migrated a global suite of tools for tracking panelist data aggregation from legacy infrastructure to AWS.

Senior Web Developer

BIAC

ii 09/2017 - 07/2021

- Led a team of 8 developers in the development of an enterprise platform using React.
- Transitioned a large monolithic application into a microservice architecture.
- Worked in DevOps with AWS (Amazon Web Services), Docker, Node, and Python development environments and specialized in Jira.
- Co-led the development of PRNCPL, a single-page application focused on managing data and customers tailored for art shows using Vue and Vuex.
- Worked as a developer in the team for designing and developing the application using Microsoft advanced technologies .Net, C#, ASP.NET3.0, SQL Server and Microsoft Visual SourceSafe.
- Engaged initially as a contractor to upgrade the front end of KeyBank's corporate banking portal, KeyNavigator, from the AngularJS-based Backbase LaunchPad widget architecture to the Angular 8-based Backbase Widget Architecture 3.
- Built a Node.js-based library, which acted as middleware for Express.js and Koa, that automatically captured user errors and sent them to a platform that aggregated and visualized them.
- Used various technologies, including cloud providers such as AWS, GCP, Azure, GitHub actions, Jira, Grafana, Prometheus, and alert manager.

Junior Web Developer

Ladoo

ii 11/2014 - 08/2017

- Fixed bugs designed websites as a junior web developer.
- And then designed a project and database reviewed other team member's code.
- Collaborated with 5 team members to develop, maintain, and improve 10+ web-based applications.
- Created the front end of an invoice management app written in React. It was fully responsive and had a lot of custom inputs and dynamically generated pages.
- Contributed as a part of the team that developed a new webshop app for a large retailer in Australia.
- · Also created a dashboard stats view with charts using the Recharts library.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree University of South Florida

= 2010 - 2014

SKILLS

MERN Stack	React-n	native Angu	lar Vue.js	Typescri	pt HTMI	_5 Tai	lwind CSS	Javascript
jQuery (raphQL	PHP Larave	l Python	Django	ASP.NET	C#	MySQL	MS SQL
Postgre SQI	Oracle	MongoDB	Elasticseard	ch AWS	Azure	Docker	GCP	Prometheus
Figma G	t JIRA	Web applica	Design F	Responsive	Design			